<record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><header><identifier>oai:oai.datacite.org:7138295</identifier><datestamp>2015-11-24T14:54:39Z</datestamp><setSpec>CDL</setSpec><setSpec>CDL.DRYAD</setSpec></header><metadata><oai_datacite xmlns="http://schema.datacite.org/oai/oai-1.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.datacite.org/oai/oai-1.0/ http://schema.datacite.org/oai/oai-1.0/oai.xsd"><isReferenceQuality>false</isReferenceQuality><schemaVersion>2.2</schemaVersion><datacentreSymbol>CDL.DRYAD</datacentreSymbol><payload><resource xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-2.2" xmlns:dryad="http://purl.org/dryad/terms/" xmlns:dim="http://www.dspace.org/xmlns/dspace/dim" xmlns:dspace="http://www.dspace.org/xmlns/dspace/dim" xmlns:mets="http://www.loc.gov/METS/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" metadataVersionNumber="1" lastMetadataUpdate="2006-05-04" xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-2.2 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-2.2/metadata.xsd">
  <identifier identifierType="DOI">10.5061/DRYAD.16Q70/1</identifier>
  <creators>
      <creator>
         <creatorName>Putman, Nathan</creatorName>
      </creator>
      <creator>
         <creatorName>Abreu-Grobois, Alberto</creatorName>
      </creator>
      <creator>
         <creatorName>Iturbe-Darkistade, I&#241;aky</creatorName>
      </creator>
      <creator>
         <creatorName>Putman, Emily</creatorName>
      </creator>
      <creator>
         <creatorName>Richards, Paul</creatorName>
      </creator>
      <creator>
         <creatorName>Verley, Philippe</creatorName>
      </creator>
  </creators>
  <titles>
      <title>Putman et al. Supplemental Tables - BL</title>
  </titles>
  <publisher>Dryad Digital Repository</publisher>
  <publicationYear>2015</publicationYear>
  <subjects>
      <subject>ocean circulation</subject>
      <subject>sea turtle</subject>
      <subject>oil spill</subject>
      <subject>connectivity</subject>
      <subject>distribution</subject>
      <subject>Gulf of Mexico</subject>
      <subject>Atlantic Ocean</subject>
      <subject>2005-2010</subject>
      <subject>Chelonia mydas</subject>
      <subject>Caretta caretta</subject>
      <subject>Lepidochelys kempii</subject>
  </subjects>
  <dates>
      <date dateType="Accepted">2015-11-24</date>
  </dates>
  <resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="Dataset">DataFile</resourceType>
  <relatedIdentifiers>
      <relatedIdentifier relationType="IsPartOf" relatedIdentifierType="DOI">10.5061/DRYAD.16Q70</relatedIdentifier>
  </relatedIdentifiers>
  <sizes>
      <size>43958 bytes</size>
  </sizes>
  <rights>At the request of the author, this item is embargoed until the associated article is published.</rights>
  <descriptions>
      <description descriptionType="Other">Supplemental Tables&#13;
Description of Supplemental Excel Tables (names are different tabs within the Excel Workbook)&#13;
Table S1. Connectivity. Table listing hatchling abundance, by species, for each nesting area and connectivity between those areas and the spill site. Percentage of particles backtracked from the spill site arriving from each of the nesting areas of green, loggerhead, and Kemp&#8217;s ridley turtles within a given year, scaled relative to the number of particles that encountered any nesting area during that same period. &#13;
&#13;
Table S2. Literature-Survival. Table of data used for estimating clutch size (number of eggs per nest), clutch survival, and oceanic survival.&#13;
&#13;
&#13;
Table S3. Green (number). The number of each age class of surface-pelagic green turtles from each of the twenty-four nesting areas estimated to be at the spill site based on median, maximum, and minimum estimates of oceanic survival.&#13;
&#13;
Table S4. Loggerhead (number). The number of each age class of surface-pelagic loggerhead turtles from each of the eight nesting areas estimated to be at the spill site based on median, maximum, and minimum estimates oceanic survival.&#13;
&#13;
Table S5. Kemp&#8217;s ridley (number). The number of each age class of surface-pelagic Kemp&#8217;s ridley turtles from each of the four nesting areas estimated to be at the spill site based on median, maximum, and minimum estimates of oceanic survival. Table includes results for passive drift &#8220;retentive behavior&#8221; simulations.&#13;
&#13;
Table S6. Green (percent). The percentage of survivors of each age class of oceanic-stage green turtles from each nesting area estimated to be at the spill site.&#13;
&#13;
Table S7. Loggerhead (percent). The percentage of survivors of each age class of oceanic-stage loggerhead turtles from each nesting area estimated to be at the spill.&#13;
&#13;
Table S8. Kemp&#8217;s ridley (percent). The percentage of the total survivors of each age class of surface-pelagic Kemp&#8217;s ridley turtles from each nesting area estimated to be at the spill site. Table includes results for passive drift &#8220;retentive behavior&#8221; simulations.</description>
  </descriptions>
</resource></payload></oai_datacite></metadata></record>
